The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Hey, everybody.
教授：大家好。
You ready to learn some algorithms?
您准备学习一些算法吗？
Yeah!
是的
Let's do it.
我们开始做吧。
I'm Eric Domain.
我是Eric Domain。
You can call me Eric.
你可以叫我埃里克。
And the last class, we sort of jumped into things.
在最后一堂课中，我们跳入了各种事物。
We studied peak finding and looked
我们研究了峰发现并看了看
at a bunch of algorithms for peak finding
一堆寻找峰的算法
on your problem set.
在您的问题集上。
You've already seen a bunch more.
您已经看到了更多。
And in this class, we're going to do some more algorithms.
在这一课中，我们将做更多的算法。
Don't worry.
不用担心
That will be at the end.
那将是最后。
We're going to talk about another problem, document
我们将讨论另一个问题，文件
distance, which will be a running example for a bunch
距离，这将是一堆连续的例子
of topics that we cover in this class.
本课程中涵盖的主题。
But before we go there, I wanted to take a step back and talk
但是在我们去那里之前，我想退后一步再谈
about, what actually is an algorithm?
关于，什么是算法？
What is an algorithm allowed to do?
允许执行什么算法？
And also deep philosophical questions like, what is time?
还有深层次的哲学问题，例如什么是时间？
What is the running time of an algorithm?
算法的运行时间是多少？
How do we measure it?
我们如何衡量？
And what are the rules the game?
游戏的规则是什么？
For fun, I thought I would first mention
为了娱乐，我想我首先要提到
where the word comes from, the word algorithm.
单词来自哪里，单词算法。
It comes from this guy, a little hard to spell.
它来自这个家伙，有点难拼写。
Al-Khwarizmi, who is sort of the father of algebra.
Al-Khwarizmi，他是代数之父。
He wrote this book called "The Compendious Book on Calculation
他写了这本书，叫做“关于计算的简明书
by Completion and Balancing" back in the day.
通过完成和平衡”。
And it was in particular about how
特别是关于
to solve linear and quadratic equations.
解决线性和二次方程式。
So the beginning of algebra.
因此是代数的开始。
I don't think he invented those techniques.
我不认为他发明了那些技术。
But he was sort of the textbook writer
但他有点像教科书作家
who wrote sort of how people solved them.
他写了人们如何解决它们的书。
And you can think of how to solve
您可以想到如何解决
those equations as early algorithms.
这些方程式是早期算法。
First, you take this number.
首先，您使用这个数字。
You multiply by this.
你乘以这个。
You add it or you reduce to squares, whatever.
可以添加它，也可以减少到正方形。
So that's where the word algebra comes from and also
这就是代数这个词的来源
where the word algorithm comes from.
单词算法来自哪里。
There aren't very many words with these roots.
这些词根有很少的词。
So there you go.
所以你去了。
Some fun history.
一些有趣的历史。
What's an algorithm?
什么是算法？
I'll start with sort of some informal definitions
我将从一些非正式的定义开始
and then the point of this lecture.
然后是本讲座的重点。
And the idea of a model of computation
还有计算模型的想法
is to formally specify what an algorithm is.
是正式指定什么是算法。
I don't want to get super technical and formal here,
我不想在这里获得超级技术性和正式性，
but I want to give you some grounding
但我想给你一些基础
so when we write Python code, when we write pseudocode,
因此，当我们编写Python代码，编写伪代码时，
we have some idea what things actually cost.
我们知道事情的实际成本。
This is a new lecture.
这是新演讲。
We've never done this before in 006.
在006年之前，我们从未做到过。
But I think it's important.
但我认为这很重要。
So at a high level, you can think
因此，从高层次上，您可以考虑
of an algorithm is just a-- I'm sure you've
一种算法只是-我确定你已经
seen the definition before.
之前看过定义。
It's a way to define computation or computational procedure
这是定义计算或计算过程的一种方式
for solving some problem.
解决一些问题。
So whereas computer code, I mean,
因此，我的意思是计算机代码
it could just be running in the background
它可能只是在后台运行
all the time doing whatever.
一直在做什么。
An algorithm we think of as having some input
我们认为有一些输入的算法
and generating some output.
并产生一些输出。
Usually, it's to solve some problem.
通常，这是为了解决一些问题。
You want to know is this number prime, whatever.
您想知道这个数字是素数吗？
Question?
题？
AUDIENCE: Can you turn up the volume for your mic?
听众：可以调高麦克风的音量吗？
PROFESSOR: This microphone does not feed into the AV system.
教授：此麦克风未插入AV系统。
So I shall just talk louder, OK?
所以我要大声说话，好吗？
And quiet the set, please.
请安静一下。
OK, so that's an algorithm.
好，那是一个算法。
You take some input.
您需要一些输入。
You run it through.
您运行通过。
You compute some output.
您计算一些输出。
Of course, computer code can do this too.
当然，计算机代码也可以做到这一点。
An algorithm is basically the mathematical analog
算法基本上是数学模拟
of a computer program.
计算机程序。
So if you want to reason about what computer programs do,
因此，如果您想知道计算机程序的功能，
you translate it into the world algorithms.
您将其转换为世界算法。
And vice versa, you want to solve some problem-- first,
反之亦然，您想解决一些问题-首先，
you usually develop an algorithm using mathematics,
您通常使用数学来开发算法，
using this class.
使用此类。
And then you convert it into computer code.
然后将其转换为计算机代码。
And this class is about that transition from one
这节课是关于从一个
to the other.
到另一个。
You can draw a picture of sort of analogs.
您可以画一幅类似的图画。
So an algorithm is a mathematical analog
所以算法是数学的模拟
of a computer program.
计算机程序。
A computer program is built on top of a programming language.
计算机程序是建立在编程语言之上的。
And it's written in a programming language.
它是用编程语言编写的。
The mathematical analog of a programming language,
编程语言的数学模拟，
what we write algorithms in, usually we
我们用什么编写算法，通常我们
write them in pseudocode, which is basically
用伪代码写出来，基本上
another fancy word for structured English,
结构化英语的另一个花哨词，
good English, whatever you want to say.
良好的英语，无论您想说什么。
Of course, you could use another natural language.
当然，您可以使用其他自然语言。
But the idea is, you need to express that algorithm in a way
但想法是，您需要以某种方式表达该算法
that people can understand and reason about formally.
人们可以正式理解并推理的内容。
So that's the structured part.
这就是结构化的部分。
Pseudocode means lots of different things.
伪代码意味着很多不同的东西。
It's just sort of an abstract how you would write down
这只是一个摘要，您将如何写下来
formal specification without necessarily being
正式规范，不一定要
able to actually run it on a computer.
能够在计算机上实际运行它。
Though there's a particular pseudocode in your textbook
虽然教科书中有特定的伪代码
which you probably could run on a computer.
您可能可以在计算机上运行。
A lot of it, anyway.
无论如何，很多。
But you don't have to use that version.
但是您不必使用该版本。
It just makes sense to humans who do the mathematics.
这对做数学的人来说才有意义。
OK, and then ultimately, this program runs on a computer.
单击确定，然后最终，该程序在计算机上运行。
You all have computers, probably in your pockets.
你们都有电脑，可能在您的口袋里。
There's an analog of a computer in the mathematical world.
在数学世界中，有一台计算机的类似物。
And that is the model of computation.
那就是计算模型。
And that's sort of the focus of the first part of this lecture.
这就是本讲座第一部分的重点。
Model of computation says what your computer is allowed to do,
计算模型表明您的计算机可以执行的操作，
what it can do in constant time, basically?
基本上，它可以在固定时间内做什么？
And that's what I want to talk about here.
这就是我在这里要谈的。
So the model of computation specifies basically
所以计算模型基本上指定
what operations you can do in an algorithm
您可以在算法中执行哪些操作
and how much they cost.
以及它们的价格。
This is the what is time.
这就是时间。
So for each operation, we're going
因此，对于每个操作，我们将
to specify how much time it costs.
指定花费多少时间。
Then the algorithm does a bunch of operations.
然后，该算法执行一堆操作。
They're combined together with control flow,
它们与控制流结合在一起，
for loops, if statements, stuff like that which we're not
for循环，if语句，诸如此类的东西
going to worry about too much.
会担心太多。
But obviously, we'll use them a lot.
但是显然，我们会经常使用它们。
And what we count is how much do each of the operations cost.
我们计算的是每个运营成本。
You add them up.
您将它们加起来。
That is the total cost of your algorithm.
那就是算法的总成本。
So in particular, we care mostly in this class
所以特别地，我们主要在这个班级
about running time.
关于运行时间。
Each operation has a time cost.
每个操作都有时间成本。
You add those up.
您将它们加起来。
That's running time of the algorithm.
那是算法的运行时间。
OK, so let's-- I'm going to cover two models of computation
好的，让我们-我将介绍两种计算模型
which you can just think of as different ways of thinking.
您可以将其视为不同的思维方式。
You've probably seen them in some sense
您可能从某种意义上看过他们
as-- what you call them?
作为-你叫他们什么？
Styles of programming.
编程风格。
Object oriented style of programming, more assembly
面向对象的编程风格，更多的汇编
style of programming.
编程风格。
There's lots of different styles of programming languages
有许多不同风格的编程语言
which I'm not going to talk about here.
我在这里不打算讨论。
But you've see analogs if you've seen those before.
但是，如果您以前曾经看过类似物，那么您已经看到过类似物。
And these models really give you a way
这些模型确实为您提供了一种方法
of structuring your thinking about how
关于如何思考的构想
you write an algorithm.
你写一个算法。
So they are the random access machine and the pointer
所以它们是随机访问机器和指针
machine.
机。
So we'll start with random access machine, also known
所以我们将从随机存取机开始
as the RAM.
作为RAM。
Can someone tell me what else RAM stands for?
有人可以告诉我RAM代表什么吗？
AUDIENCE: Random Access Memory?
听众：随机存取存储器？
PROFESSOR: Random Access Memory.
教授：随机存取存储器。
So this is both confusing but also convenience.
因此，这既混乱又方便。
Because RAM simultaneously stands for two things
因为RAM同时代表两件事
and they mean almost the same thing, but not quite.
他们的意思几乎相同，但不完全相同。
So I guess that's more confusing than useful.
因此，我认为这比有用更令人困惑。
But there you go.
但是，你去了。
So we have random access memory.
所以我们有随机存取存储器。
Oh, look at that.
哦，看那个。
Fits perfectly.
非常适合。
And so we're thinking, this is a real--
所以我们在想，这是真实的-
this is-- random access memory is over here in real computer
这是-实际计算机中的随机存取存储器在这里
land.
土地。
That's like, D-RAM SD-RAM, whatever--
就像D-RAM SD-RAM，
the things you buy and stick into your motherboard, your GP,
您购买并粘贴在主板，GP上的东西，
or whatever.
管他呢。
And over here, the mathematical analog of-- so here's,
在这里，...的数学模拟
it's a RAM.
这是一个RAM。
Here, it's also a RAM.
在这里，它也是一个RAM。
Here, it's a random access machine.
在这里，这是一台随机访问的机器。
Here, it's a random access memory.
在这里，它是一个随机存取存储器。
It's technical detail.
这是技术细节。
But the idea is, if you look at RAM that's in your computer,
但想法是，如果您查看计算机中的RAM，
it's basically a giant array, right?
它基本上是一个巨大的阵列，对不对？
You can go from zero to, I don't know.
您不知道可以从零到零。
A typical chip these days is like four gigs in one thing.
这些天的典型芯片在一件事上就像四场演出。
So you can go from zero to four gigs.
因此，您可以从零到四个演出。
You can access anything in the middle there in constant time.
您可以在恒定时间内访问中间的任何内容。
To access something, you need to know where it is.
要访问某物，您需要知道它在哪里。
That's random access memory.
那是随机存取存储器。
So that's an array.
所以这是一个数组。
So I'll just draw a big picture.
所以我会画一幅大图。
Here's an array.
这是一个数组。
Now, RAM is usually organized by words.
现在，RAM通常是按单词组织的。
So these are a machine word, which
这些是机器字，
we're going to put in this model.
我们将采用这种模型。
And then there's address zero, address one, address two.
然后是地址零，地址一，地址二。
This is the fifth word.
这是第五个字。
And just keeps going.
并且继续前进。
You can think of this as infinite.
您可以认为这是无限的。
Or the amount that you use, that's
或您使用的金额，即
the space of your algorithm, if you care about storage space.
算法的空间（如果您关心存储空间）。
So that's basically it.
基本上就是这样。
OK, now how do we-- this is the memory side of things.
好的，现在我们该怎么做-这就是事物的记忆方面。
How do we actually compute with it?
我们如何实际计算呢？
It's very simple.
非常简单
We just say, in constant time, an algorithm can basically
我们只是说，在恒定时间内，算法可以
read in or load a constant number of words from memory,
从内存中读取或加载恒定数量的单词，
do a constant number of computations on them,
对它们进行恒定数量的计算，
and then write them out.
然后写出来。
It's usually called store.
通常称为商店。
OK, it needs to know where these words are.
好的，它需要知道这些单词在哪里。
It accesses them by address.
它通过地址访问它们。
And so I guess I should write here
所以我想我应该在这里写
you have a constant number of registers just hanging around.
您有固定数量的寄存器随处可见。
So you load some words into registers.
因此，您将一些单词加载到寄存器中。
You can do some computations on those registers.
您可以对那些寄存器进行一些计算。
And then you can write them back,
然后你可以写回去
storing them in locations that are
将它们存储在
specified by your registers.
由您的寄存器指定。
So you've ever done assembly programming,
这样您就完成了汇编编程，
this is what assembly programming is like.
这就是汇编编程的样子。
And it can be rather annoying to write algorithms in this model.
在此模型中编写算法可能会很烦人。
But in some sense, it is reality.
但是从某种意义上说，这是现实。
This is how we think about computers.
这就是我们对计算机的看法。
If you ignore things like caches,
如果您忽略诸如缓存之类的内容，
this is an accurate model of computation
这是一个精确的计算模型
that loading, computing, and storing
加载，计算和存储
all take roughly the same amount of time.
全部花费大致相同的时间。
They all take constant time.
他们都花固定的时间。
You can manipulate a whole word at a time.
您可以一次操纵整个单词。
Now, what exactly is a word?
现在，一个字到底是什么？
You know, computers these days, it's like 32 bits or 64 bits.
您知道，如今的计算机就像32位或64位。
But we like to be a little bit more abstract.
但是，我们希望更加抽象一些。
A word is w bits.
一个字是w位。
It's slightly annoying.
有点烦人。
And most of this class, we won't really worry about what w is.
在本课程的大部分时间里，我们都不会真正担心w是什么。
We'll assume that we're given as input
我们假设我们被作为输入
a bunch of things which are words.
一堆东​​西就是文字。
So for example, peak finding.
因此，例如峰发现。
We're given a matrix of numbers.
我们得到了一个数字矩阵。
We didn't really say whether they're integers or floats
我们没有真正说出它们是整数还是浮点数
or what.
要不然是啥。
We don't worry about that.
我们不用担心。
We just think of them as words and we
我们只是将它们视为单词，而我们
assume that we can manipulate those words.
假设我们可以操纵这些单词。
In particular, given two numbers, we can compare them.
特别是，给定两个数字，我们可以对其进行比较。
Which is bigger?
哪个更大？
And so we can determine, is this cell in the matrix
这样我们可以确定矩阵中的这个单元格
a peak by comparing it with its neighbors in constant time.
通过在恒定时间内将其与邻域进行比较来形成一个峰值。
We didn't say why it was constant time to do that.
我们没有说为什么要持续这样做。
But now you kind of know.
但是现在您知道了。
If those things are all words and you
如果这些都是言语而你
can manipulate a constant number of words in constant time,
可以在恒定时间内操纵恒定数量的单词，
you can tell whether a number is a peak in constant time.
您可以判断一个数字是否是恒定时间的峰值。
Some things like w should be at least log the size of memory.
诸如w之类的东西至少应记录日志的内存大小。
Because my word should be able to specify
因为我的话应该能够说明
an index into this array.
该数组的索引。
And we might use that someday.
我们可能有一天会使用它。
But basically, don't worry about it.
但基本上，不用担心。
Words are words.
单词就是单词。
Words come in as inputs.
单词作为输入进来。
You can manipulate them and you don't
您可以操纵它们，而您却不能
have to worry about it for the most part.
大部分时候都需要担心。
In unit four of this class, we're
在本课程的第四单元中，我们是
going to talk about, what if we have really giant integers that
要谈论的是，如果我们有真正的巨型整数
don't fit in a word?
一句话不适合吗？
How do we manipulate them?
我们如何操纵它们？
How do we add them, multiply them?
我们如何相加，相乘？
So that's another topic.
这是另一个话题。
But most of this class, we'll just
但是在这堂课的大部分时间里
assume everything we're given is one word.
假设我们得到的一切都是一个字。
And it's easy to compute on.
而且很容易计算。
So this is a realistic model, more or less.
因此，这或多或少是一个现实的模型。
And it's a powerful one.
这是一个强大的功能。
But a lot of the time, a lot of code
但是很多时候，很多代码
just doesn't use arrays-- doesn't need it.
只是不使用数组-不需要它。
Sometimes we need arrays, sometimes we don't.
有时我们需要数组，有时我们不需要。
Sometimes you feel like a nut, sometimes you don't.
有时您感觉像个坚果，有时却不。
So it's useful to think about somewhat more abstract models
因此，考虑更多抽象模型很有用
that are not quite as powerful but offer a simpler
并不那么强大，但提供了更简单的方法
way of thinking about things.
思考事物的方式。
For example, in this model there's
例如，在此模型中
no dynamic memory allocation.
没有动态内存分配。
You probably know you could implement dynamic memory
您可能知道可以实现动态内存
allocation because real computers do it.
分配，因为真正的计算机可以做到。
But it's nice to think about a model
但是考虑一个模型真是太好了
where that's taken care of for you.
照顾您的地方。
It's kind of like a higher level programming abstraction.
有点像更高层次的编程抽象。
So the one is useful in this class is the pointer machine.
因此在此类中有用的是指针计算机。
This basically corresponds to object oriented programming
这基本上对应于面向对象的编程
in a simple, very simple version.
在一个非常简单的版本中。
So we have dynamically allocated objects.
因此，我们已经动态分配了对象。
And an object has a constant number of fields.
一个对象具有恒定数量的字段。
And a field is going to be either a word-- so you
一个字段将是一个单词-所以你
can think of this as, for example,
可以这样认为，
storing an integer, one of the input objects
存储整数，输入对象之一
or something you computed on it or a counter, all these sorts
或您在其上计算过的东西或计数器，所有这些种类
of things-- or a pointer.
的东西-或指针。
And that's where pointer machine gets its name.
这就是指针机的名称。
A pointer is something that points to another object
指针是指向另一个对象的东西
or has a special value null, also known as nil,
或具有特殊值null（也称为nil），
also known as none in Python.
在Python中也称为none。
OK, how many people have heard about pointers before?
好，以前有多少人听说过指针？
Who hasn't?
谁没有？
Willing to admit it?
愿意承认吗？
OK, only a few.
好，只有几个。
That's good.
那很好。
You should have seen pointers.
您应该已经看到了指针。
You may have heard them called references.
您可能听说过它们称为参考。
Modern languages these days don't call them pointers
如今，现代语言不再称其为指针
because pointers are scary.
因为指针很可怕。
But there's a very subtle difference between them.
但是它们之间有一个非常细微的差异。
And this model actually really is references.
这个模型实际上是参考。
But for whatever reason, it's called a pointer machine.
但是无论出于什么原因，它都被称为指针机。
It doesn't matter.
没关系
The point is, you've seem linked lists I hope.
关键是，您似乎希望找到链表。
And linked lists have a bunch of fields in each node.
链接列表在每个节点中都有一堆字段。
Maybe you've got a pointer to the previous element,
也许您有一个指向上一个元素的指针，
a pointer to the next element, and some value.
指向下一个元素的指针和一些值。
So here's a very simple linked list.
因此，这是一个非常简单的链表。
This is what you'd call a doubly linked list because it
这就是您所说的双向链接列表，因为它
has previous and next pointers.
具有上一个和下一个指针。
So the next pointer points to this node.
因此，下一个指针指向此节点。
The previous pointer points to this node.
前一个指针指向此节点。
Next pointer points to null.
下一个指针指向null。
The previous pointer points to null, let's say.
假设前一个指针指向null。
So that's a two node doubly linked list.
这就是两个节点的双向链表。
You presume we have a pointer to the head of the list,
您假设我们有一个指向列表开头的指针，
maybe a pointer to the tail of list, whatever.
也许是指向列表尾部的指针，无论如何。
So this is a structure in the pointer machine.
因此，这是指针机中的结构。
It's a data structure.
这是一个数据结构。
In Python, you might call this a named tuple,
在Python中，您可以将其称为命名元组，
or it's just an object with three attributes,
或仅仅是具有三个属性的对象，
I guess, they're called in Python.
我猜，它们在Python中被称为。
So here we have the value.
因此，在这里我们具有价值。
That's a word like an integer.
那是一个像整数的词。
And then some things can be pointers
然后一些东西可以成为指针
that point to other nodes.
指向其他节点。
And you can create a new node.
您可以创建一个新节点。
You can destroy a node.
您可以销毁节点。
That's the dynamic memory allocation.
这就是动态内存分配。
In this model, yeah, pointers are pointers.
是的，在这种模型中，指针就是指针。
You can't touch them.
你不能碰他们。
Now, you can implement this model in a random access
现在，您可以在随机访问中实现此模型
machine.
机。
A pointer becomes an index into this giant table.
指针成为该巨型表的索引。
And that's more like the pointers in C
那更像是C中的指针
if you've ever written C programs.
如果您曾经编写过C程序。
Because then you can take a pointer
因为那样你就可以指针
and you can add one to it and go to the next thing after that.
您可以在其中添加一个，然后转到下一个内容。
In this model, you can just follow a pointer.
在此模型中，您可以仅跟随一个指针。
That's all you can do.
那就是您所能做的。
OK, following a pointer costs constant time.
好的，跟随指针花费的时间是恒定的。
Changing one of these fields costs constant time.
更改这些字段之一将花费固定的时间。
All the usual things you might imagine doing to these objects
您可能会想到对这些对象执行的所有常规操作
take constant time.
花费固定的时间。
So it's actually a weaker model than this one.
因此，它实际上是比这个模型更弱的模型。
Because you could implement a pointer machine
因为您可以实现一个指针机
with a random access machine.
用随机存取机。
But it offers a different way of thinking.
但这提供了不同的思维方式。
A lot of data structures are built this way.
这种方式构建了许多数据结构。
Cool.
凉。
So that's the theory side.
这就是理论方面。
What I'd like to talk about next is actually in Python,
接下来我要说的实际上是Python，
what's a reasonable model of what's going on?
发生什么情况的合理模型是什么？
So these are old models.
因此，这些都是旧模型。
This goes back to the '80s.
这可以追溯到80年代。
This one probably '80s or '70s.
这个大概是80年代或70年代。
So they've been around a long time.
因此，他们已经存在了很长时间。
People have used them forever.
人们永远使用它们。
Python is obviously much more recent, at least
Python显然是最近的，至少
modern versions of Python.
现代版本的Python。
And it's the model of computation in some sense
从某种意义上讲，它是计算模型
that we use in this class.
我们在本课中使用的。
Because we're implementing everything in Python.
因为我们正在用Python实现所有内容。
And Python offers both a random access machine perspective
Python提供了随机访问机器的观点
because it has arrays, and it offers a pointer machine
因为它具有数组，并且提供了指针机
perspective because it has references,
透视，因为它有参考，
because it has pointers.
因为它有指针。
So you can do either one.
所以你可以做任何一个。
But it also has a lot of operations.
但是它也有很多操作。
It doesn't just have load and store and follow pointer.
它不仅具有加载，存储和跟随指针的功能。
It's got things like sort and append
它具有排序和附加之类的功能
and concatenation of two lists and lots of things.
和两个列表和很多东西的串联。
And each of those has a cost associated with them.
而每个人都有与之相关的成本。
So whereas the random access machine and pointer machine,
因此，尽管随机存取机和指针机
they're theoretical models.
它们是理论模型。
They're designed to be super simple.
它们的设计非常简单。
So it's clear that everything you do takes constant time.
显然，您所做的每一件事都需要花费固定的时间。
In Python, some of the operations you can do
在Python中，您可以执行一些操作
take a lot of time.
花很多时间。
Some of the operations in Python take exponential time to do.
Python中的某些操作需要花费大量时间。
And you've got to know when you're writing your algorithms
而且您必须知道何时编写算法
down either thinking in a Python model or your implementing
在Python模型中思考或实现
your algorithms in actual Python,
您在实际Python中的算法，
which operations are fast and which are slow.
哪些操作快，哪些操作慢。
And that's what I'd like to spend the next few minutes on.
这就是我接下来要花费的时间。
There's a lot of operations.
有很多操作。
I'm not going to cover all of them.
我不会覆盖所有这些。
But we'll cover more in recitation.
但是我们将在背诵中介绍更多内容。
And there's a whole bunch in my notes.
我的笔记里有一堆。
I won't get to all of them.
我不会全部了解。
So in Python, you can do random access style things.
因此，在Python中，您可以执行随机访问样式的事情。
In Python, arrays are called lists,
在Python中，数组称为列表，
which is super confusing.
超级混乱。
But there you go.
但是，你去了。
A list in Python is an array in real world.
Python中的列表是现实世界中的数组。
It's a super cool array, of course?
当然，这是一个非常酷的阵列？
And you can think of it as a list.
您可以将其视为列表。
But in terms implementation, it's implemented as an array.
但就实现而言，它是作为数组实现的。
Question?
题？
AUDIENCE: I thought that [INAUDIBLE].
听众：我认为[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: You thought Python links lists were linked lists.
教授：您认为Python链接列表是链接列表。
That's why it's so confusing.
这就是为什么它如此令人困惑。
In fact, they are not.
实际上，事实并非如此。
In, say, scheme, back in the days when we taught scheme,
例如，在计划中，当我们教计划的时候，
lists are linked lists.
列表是链接列表。
And it's very different.
这是非常不同的。
So when you do-- I'll give an operation here.
所以，当您这样做时，我将在此处进行操作。
You have a list L, and you do something like this.
您有一个列表L，您会执行以下操作。
L is a list object.
L是列表对象。
This takes constant time.
这需要固定的时间。
In a linked list, it would take linear time.
在链接列表中，将花费线性时间。
Because we've got a scan to position I, scan to position J,
因为我们已经扫描到位置I，所以扫描到位置J，
add 5, and store.
加5，然后存储。
But conveniently in Python, this takes constant time.
但是在Python中很方便，这需要持续的时间。
And that's important to know.
这一点很重要。
I know that the terminology is super confusing.
我知道术语超级混乱。
But blame the benevolent dictator for life.
但是要怪仁慈的独裁者一生。
On the other hand, you can do style two, pointer machine,
另一方面，您可以进行样式二，指针机，
using object oriented programming, obviously.
显然，使用面向对象的编程。
I'll just mention that I'm not really
我只想说我不是真的
worrying about methods here.
担心这里的方法。
Because methods are just sort of a way of thinking about things,
因为方法只是一种思考事物的方式，
not super important from a cost standpoint.
从成本的角度来看并不是很重要。
If your object has a constant number of attributes--
如果您的对象具有恒定数量的属性，
it can't have like a million attributes
它不能具有一百万个属性
or can't have n executes-- then it
或没有n执行-那么它
fits into this pointer machine model.
适合此指针机模型。
So if you have an object that only
因此，如果您只有一个物体
has like three things or 10 things or whatever,
有三件事或十件事等等
that's a pointer machine.
那是一个指针机。
You can think of manipulating that object
您可以考虑操纵该对象
as taking constant time.
因为需要固定的时间。
If you are screwing around the object's dictionary
如果您正在拧紧对象的字典
and doing lots of crazy things, then you
做很多疯狂的事情，那么你
have to be careful about whether this remains true.
必须注意是否仍然如此。
But as long as you only have a reasonable number
但是只要你有一个合理的数字
of attributes, this is all fair game.
属性，这都是公平的游戏。
And so if you do something like, if you're implementing a linked
因此，如果您执行类似操作，
list, Python I checked still does not
列表，我检查过的Python仍然没有
have built-in linked lists.
具有内置的链接列表。
They're pretty easy to build, though.
但是，它们很容易构建。
You have a pointer.
你有一个指针。
And you just say x equals x.next.
您只说x等于x.next。
That takes constant time because accessing this field
这需要持续的时间，因为访问此字段
in an object of constant size takes constant time.
大小恒定的对象花费的时间不变。
And we don't care what these constants are.
而且我们不在乎这些常量是什么。
That's the beauty of algorithms.
那就是算法的美。
Because we only care about scalability with n.
因为我们只关心n的可伸缩性。
There's no n here.
这里没有人。
This takes constant time.
这需要固定的时间。
No matter how big your linked list
无论您的链表多大
is or no matter how many objects you have,
不管有多少物体，
these are constant time.
这些是恒定的时间。
OK, let's do some harder ones, though.
好的，让我们做一些更难的事情。
In general, the idea is, if you take
一般来说，如果
an operation like L.append-- so you have a list.
L.append之类的操作-这样您就有了一个列表。
And you want to append some item to the list.
您想将一些项目添加到列表中。
It's an array, though.
不过，这是一个数组。
So think about it.
所以考虑一下。
The way to figure out how much does this cost
弄清楚这要花多少钱的方法
is to think about how it's implemented
考虑如何实施
in terms of these basic operations.
在这些基本操作方面。
So these are your sort of the core concept time things.
因此，这些是您的核心概念时间事物。
Most everything can be reduced to thinking about this.
大多数事情都可以简化为思考。
But sometimes, it's less obvious.
但是有时候，它并不那么明显。
L.apend is a little tricky to think about.
L.apend的思考有点棘手。
Because basically, you have an array of some size.
因为基本上，您有一些大小的数组。
And now you want to make an array one larger.
现在，您想将数组扩大一个。
And the obvious way to do that is to allocate a new array
显而易见的方法是分配一个新数组
and copy all the elements.
并复制所有元素。
That would take linear time.
这将花费线性时间。
Python doesn't do that.
Python不会那样做。
What does it do?
它有什么作用？
Stay tuned for lecture eight.
请继续关注第八讲。
It does something called table doubling.
它执行称为表加倍的操作。
It's a very simple idea.
这是一个非常简单的想法。
You can almost get guess it from the title.
您几乎可以从标题中猜到它。
And if you go to lecture-- is it eight or nine?
如果您去听课，是八九吗？
Nine, sorry.
九，对不起。
You'll see how this can basically
您将基本了解
be done in constant time.
在固定时间内完成。
There's a slight catch, but basically, think of it
有一点收获，但基本上，请考虑一下
as a constant time operation.
作为恒定时间操作。
Once we have that, and so this is
一旦有了，就这样
why you should take this class so you'll
为什么要上这堂课
understand how Python works.
了解Python的工作原理。
This is using an algorithmic concept that was invented,
这使用了发明的算法概念，
I don't know, decades ago, but is a simple thing
我不知道，几十年前，但这很简单
that we need to do to solve lots of other problems.
解决很多其他问题需要做的事情。
So it's cool.
太酷了。
There's a lot of features in Python that use algorithms.
Python中有很多使用算法的功能。
And that's kind of why I'm telling you.
这就是为什么我告诉你。
All right, so let's do another one.
好吧，让我们再做一个。
A little easier.
容易一点。
What if I want to concatenate two lists?
如果要串联两个列表怎么办？
You should know in Python this is a non-destructive operation.
您应该知道在Python中这是一种非破坏性的操作。
You basically take a copy of L1 and L2 and concatenate them.
您基本上可以复制L1和L2并将它们连接起来。
Of course, they're arrays.
当然，它们是数组。
The way to think about this is to re-implement it
思考此问题的方法是重新实现它
as Python code.
作为Python代码。
This is the same thing as saying, well,
这和说，是一样的，
L is initially empty.
L最初是空的。
And then for every item x and L1, L.append(x).
然后对于每个项x和L1，L.append（x）。
And a lot of the times in documentation for Python,
很多时候在Python文档中，
you see this sort of here's what it means, especially
您会看到这种意思，尤其是
in the fancier features.
在更高级的功能上。
They give sort of an equivalent simple Python, if you will.
如果可以的话，它们提供了等效的简单Python。
This doesn't use any fancy operations
这不使用任何花哨的操作
that we haven't seen already.
我们还没有看到。
So now we know this takes constant time.
所以现在我们知道这需要持续的时间。
The append, this append, takes constant time.
附件（此附件）需要固定的时间。
And so the amount of time here is basically
所以这里的时间基本上是
order the length of L1.
订购L1的长度。
And the time here is order the length of L2.
而这里的时间是L2的长度。
And so in total, it's order-- I'm
总的来说，这是命令-我是
going to be careful and say 1 plus length of L1
要小心，说1加L1的长度
plus length of L2.
加上L2的长度
The 1 plus is just in case these are both 0.
如果它们都是0，则加1。
It still takes constant time to build an initial list.
建立初始列表仍然需要花费固定的时间。
OK, so there are a bunch of operations
好，所以有很多操作
that are written in these notes.
这些注释中写的。
I'm not going to go through all of them
我不会经历所有的
because they're tedious.
因为它们很乏味。
But a lot of you, could just expand out code like this.
但是你们中的很多人都可以像这样扩展代码。
And it's very easy to analyze.
而且非常容易分析。
Whereas you just look at plus, you
而您只看加号
think, oh, plus is constant time.
想想，哦，加上是恒定的时间。
And plus is constant time if this is a word
如果这是一个字，那么加号就是固定时间
and this is a word.
这是一个词。
But these are entire data structures.
但是这些都是完整的数据结构。
And so it's not constant time.
因此，时间不是固定的。
All right.
好吧。
There are more subtle fun ones to think about.
还有更多有趣的事情要考虑。
Like, if I want to know is x in the list, how does that happen?
就像，如果我想知道列表中的x，这是怎么发生的？
Any guesses?
有什么猜想吗？
There's an operator in Python called
Python中有一个运算子叫做
in-- x in L. How long do you think this takes?
in-- x inL。您认为这需要多长时间？
Altogether?
共？
Linear, yeah.
线性，是的。
Linear time.
线性时间。
In the worst case, you're going to have
在最坏的情况下，您将拥有
to scan through the whole list.
扫描整个列表。
Lists aren't necessarily sorted.
列表不一定要排序。
We don't know anything about them.
我们对他们一无所知。
So you've got to just scan through and test
因此，您只需要扫描并测试
for every item.
对于每个项目。
Is x equal to that item?
x等于那个项目吗？
And it's even worse if equal equals costs a lot.
如果等于等于付出很多代价，那就更糟了。
So if x is some really complicated thing,
因此，如果x是一件非常复杂的事情，
you have to take that into account.
您必须考虑到这一点。
OK, blah, blah, blah.
好吧，等等，等等。
OK, another fun one.
好，另一个有趣的。
This is like a pop quiz.
这就像一个流行测验。
How long's it take to compute the length of a list?
计算列表的长度需要多长时间？
Constant.
不变。
Yeah, luckily, if you didn't know anything,
是的，幸运的是，如果您什么都不知道，
you'd have to scan through the list and count the items.
您必须浏览列表并计算项目。
But in Python, lists are implemented
但是在Python中，列表已实现
with a counter built in.
内置计数器。
It always stores the list at the beginning--
它总是将列表存储在开头-
stores the length of the list at the beginning.
将列表的长度存储在开头。
So you just look it up.
因此，您只需查找一下即可。
This is instantaneous.
这是瞬时的。
It's important, though.
这很重要。
That can matter.
那很重要。
All right.
好吧。
Let's do some more.
让我们做更多。
What if I want to sort a list?
如果我想对列表进行排序怎么办？
How long does that take?
这需要多长时间？
N log n where n is the length of the list.
N log n其中n是列表的长度。
Technically times the time to compare two items, which
从技术上讲，比较两个项目的时间乘以
usually we're just sorting words.
通常我们只是对单词进行排序。
And so this is constant time.
因此，这是恒定时间。
If you look at Python sorting algorithm,
如果您看一下Python排序算法，
it uses a comparison sort.
它使用比较排序。
This is the topic of lectures three and four and seven.
这是第三，第四和第七讲的主题。
But in particular, the very next lecture,
但特别是在接下来的演讲中
we will see how this is done in n log n time.
我们将看到如何在n log n时间内完成此操作。
And that is using algorithms.
那就是使用算法。
All right, let's go to dictionaries.
好吧，让我们去看看字典。
Python called dicts.
Python称为dicts。
And these let you do things.
这些让您做事。
They're a generalization of lists in some sense.
从某种意义上讲，它们是列表的概括。
Instead of putting just an index here, an integer between 0
而不是仅在此处放置索引，而是0之间的整数
and the length minus 1, you can put an arbitrary key
长度减去1，您可以放置​​任意键
and store a value, for example.
并存储一个值。
How long does this take?
这需要多长时间？
I'm not going to ask you because, it's not obvious.
我不会问你，因为这并不明显。
In fact, this is one of the most important data structures
实际上，这是最重要的数据结构之一
in all of computer science.
在所有计算机科学中。
It's called a hash table.
它称为哈希表。
And it is the topic of lectures eight through 10.
这是第8至10讲课的主题。
So stay tuned for how to do this in constant time,
因此，请继续关注如何在恒定时间内执行此操作，
how to be able to store an arbitrary key,
如何能够存储任意密钥，
get it back out in constant time.
在固定时间内将其取出。
This is assuming the key is a single word.
假设键是一个单词。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Does it first check to see whether the key is already
听众：首先检查密钥是否已经存在
in the dictionary?
在字典中？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, it will clobber any existing key.
教授：是的，它将破坏任何现有的密钥。
There's also, you know, you can test
您还可以测试
whether a key is in the dictionary.
密钥是否在字典中。
That also takes constant time.
这也需要持续的时间。
You can delete something from the dictionary.
您可以从字典中删除某些内容。
All the usual-- dealing with a single key in dictionaries,
通常-处理字典中的单个键，
obviously dictionary.update, that involves a lot of keys.
显然是dictionary.update，其中涉及很多键。
That doesn't take some time.
不需要时间。
How long does it take?
多久时间？
Well, you write out a for loop and count them.
好吧，您编写了一个for循环并对其进行计数。
AUDIENCE: But how can you see whether [INAUDIBLE]
听众：但是你怎么看[听不清]
dictionary in constant time?
字典在恒定的时间？
PROFESSOR: How do you do this in constant time?
教授：您如何在固定时间内做到这一点？
Come to lecture eight through 10.
参加第8至10堂课。
I should say a slight catch, which
我应该说一点收获，
is this is constant time with high probability.
这是恒定时间的可能性很高吗？
It's a randomized algorithm.
这是一个随机算法。
It doesn't always take constant time.
并非总是需要固定的时间。
It's always correct.
总是正确的。
But sometimes, very rarely, it takes a little more
但是有时候，很少会花更多的时间
than constant time.
而不是固定的时间。
And I'm going to abbreviate this WHP.
我将简化此WHP。
And we'll see more what that means mostly, actually,
实际上，我们将看到更多的含义，
in 6046.
在6046年。
But we'll see a fair amount in 6006 on how this works
但是我们会在6006中看到相当多的数字
and how it's possible.
以及它如何成为可能。
It's a big area of research.
这是一个很大的研究领域。
A lot of people work on hashing.
很多人从事散列工作。
It's very cool and it's super useful.
这非常酷，而且超级有用。
If you write any code these days, you use a dictionary.
如果这些天您编写任何代码，则可以使用字典。
It's the way to solve problems.
这是解决问题的方法。
I'm basically using Python is a platform
我基本上是使用Python是一个平台
to advertise the rest of the class you may have noticed.
宣传您可能已经注意到的其余课程。
Not every topic we cover in this class is already in Python,
并非我们在本课程中涵盖的所有主题都已经在Python中了，
but a lot of them are.
但是很多。
So we've got table doubling.
因此，我们将表加倍。
We've got dictionaries.
我们有字典。
We've got sorting.
我们已经排序。
Another one is longs, which are long integers in Python
另一个是long，在Python中是long整数
through version two.
通过第二版。
And this is the topic of lecture 11.
这是第11讲的主题。
And so for fun, if I have two integers x and y,
所以很有趣，如果我有两个整数x和y，
and let's say one of them is this many words long
假设其中之一是那么长
and the other one is this many words long,
另一个是这么长的字，
how long do you think it takes to add them?
您认为添加它们需要多长时间？
Guesses?
猜猜
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Plus?
教授：还有吗？
Times?
时间？
Plus is the answer.
加号就是答案。
You can do it in that much time.
您可以在那么长的时间内完成操作。
If you think about the grade school algorithm
如果您考虑年级算法
for adding really big multi-digit numbers,
用于添加非常大的多位数字，
it'll only take that much time.
只需要那么多时间。
Multiplication is a little bit harder, though.
但是，乘法要困难一些。
If you look at the grade school algorithm,
如果您看小学的算法，
it's going to be x times y-- it's quadratic time not so
这将是y的x倍-不是二次方的时间
good.
好。
The algorithm that's implemented in Python
用Python实现的算法
is x plus y to the log base 2 of 3.
对数以2为底的对数是x加y。
By the way, I always write LG to mean log base 2.
顺便说一句，我总是将LG写入对数基2。
Because it only has two letters, so OK, this is 2.
因为它只有两个字母，所以确定为2。
Log base 2 of 3 is about 1.6.
3的对数底数为2约为1.6。
So while the straightforward algorithm is basically
所以虽然简单的算法基本上是
x plus y squared, this one is x plus y to the 1.6 power,
x加y的平方，这是x加y为1.6的幂，
a little better than quadratic.
比平方好一点。
And the Python developers found that was faster
而且Python开发人员发现速度更快
than grade school multiplication.
而不是小学乘法。
And so that's what they implemented.
这就是他们所实施的。
And that is something we will cover in lecture 11,
这就是我们将在第11讲中介绍的内容
how to do that.
怎么做。
It's pretty cool.
它太酷了。
There are faster algorithms, but this
有更快的算法，但这
is one that works quite practically.
是一种非常实用的工具。
One more.
多一个。
Heap queue, this is in the Python standard library
堆队列，这在Python标准库中
and implements something called the heap, which
并实现了称为堆的东西
will be in lecture four.
将在第四讲中。
So, coming soon to a classroom near you.
因此，很快就会来到您附近的教室。
All right, enough advertisement.
好的，足够的广告。
That gives you some idea of the model of computation.
这使您对计算模型有了一些了解。
There's a whole bunch more in these notes which are online.
这些在线笔记中还有很多。
Go check them out.
去看看他们。
And some of them, we'll cover in recitation tomorrow.
其中一些，我们明天再讲。
I'd like to-- now that we are sort of comfortable for what
我想-现在我们对什么感到满意
costs what in Python, I want to do a real example.
花费了Python中的费用，我想做一个真实的例子。
So last time, we did peak finding.
所以上次，我们做了高峰发现。
We're going to have another example which
我们将有另一个例子
is called document distance.
称为文档距离。
So let's do that.
因此，让我们这样做。
Any questions before we go on?
在我们继续之前有任何疑问吗？
All right.
好吧。
So document distance problem is, I give you two documents.
所以文件距离问题是，我给你两个文件。
I'll call them D1 D2.
我称它们为D1 D2。
And I want to compute the distance between them.
我想计算它们之间的距离。
And the first question is, what does that mean?
第一个问题是，这是什么意思？
What is this distance function?
这是什么距离函数？
Let me first tell you some motivations
我先告诉你一些动机
for computing document distance.
用于计算文档距离。
Let's say you're Google and you're
假设您是Google，而您
cataloging the entire web.
对整个网络进行分类。
You'd like to know when two web pages are basically identical.
您想知道两个网页何时基本相同。
Because then you store less and because you present it
因为那样您就减少了存储量并且因为您展示了它
differently to the user.
与用户不同。
You say, well, there's this page.
您说的很好，有此页面。
And there's lots of extra copies.
而且还有很多额外的副本。
But you just need-- here's the canonical one.
但是，您只需要-这就是规范的一个。
Or you're Wikipedia.
或者你是维基百科。
And I don't know if you've ever looked at Wikipedia.
而且我不知道您是否看过Wikipedia。
There's a list of all mirrors of Wikipedia.
列出了Wikipedia的所有镜像。
There's like millions of them.
那里有数百万。
And they find them by hand.
他们是手工找到的。
But you could do that using document distance.
但是您可以使用文档距离来做到这一点。
Say, are these basically identical
说，这些基本相同
other than like some stuff at the-- junk
除了喜欢垃圾东西
at the beginning or the end?
在开始还是结束？
Or if you're teaching this class and you want to detect,
或者，如果您正在教这门课，并且想发现，
are two problem sets cheating?
是两个问题作弊吗？
Are they identical?
他们是相同的吗？
We do this a lot.
我们经常这样做。
I'm not going to tell you what distance function we use.
我不会告诉您我们使用什么距离函数。
Because that would defeat the point.
因为那样会失败。
It's not the one we cover in class.
这不是我们在课堂上讨论的内容。
But we use automated tests for whether you're cheating.
但是我们会使用自动化测试来确定您是否作弊。
I've got some more.
我还有更多。
Web search.
网络搜索。
Let's say you're Google again.
假设您再次成为Google。
And you want to implement searching.
您想实现搜索。
Like, I give you three words.
就像，我给你三个字。
I'm searching for introduction to algorithms.
我正在寻找算法的介绍。
You can think of introduction to algorithms
您可以想到算法介绍
as a very short document.
作为一个非常简短的文件。
And you want to test whether that document is
您想测试该文档是否
similar to all the other documents on the web.
类似于网络上的所有其他文档。
And the one that's most similar, the one that
最相似的那个
has the small distance, that's maybe
距离很小，也许
what you want to put at the top.
您想放在顶部的内容。
That's obviously not what Google does.
显然那不是Google所做的。
But it's part of what it does.
但这是其工作的一部分。
So that's why you might care.
这就是为什么您可能会在意。
It's partly also just a toy problem.
部分原因只是玩具问题。
It lets us illustrate a lot of the techniques
它让我们说明了很多技术
that we develop in this class.
我们在这个班上发展的。
All right, I'm going to think of a document
好吧，我要考虑一个文件
as a sequence of words.
作为一个单词序列。
Just to be a little bit more formal,
只是稍微正式一点
what do I mean by document?
文件是什么意思？
And a word is just going to be a string
一个词只是一个字符串
of alphanumeric characters-- A through Z
字母数字字符-A到Z
and zero through nine.
从零到九。
OK, so if I have a document which you also
好，如果我有一个文件，你也
think of as a string and you basically
认为是一个字符串，你基本上
delete all the white space and punctuation all the other junk
删除所有空白，并删除所有其他垃圾标点符号
that's in there.
在那里。
This Everything in between those, those are the words.
在这一切之间，那些就是单词。
That's a simple definition of decomposing documents
这是分解文档的简单定义
into words.
变成文字。
And now we can think of about what--
现在我们可以考虑一下……
I want to know whether D1 and D2 are similar.
我想知道D1和D2是否相似。
And I've thought about my document
我考虑过我的文件
as a collection of words.
作为单词的集合。
Maybe they're similar if they share a lot of words in common.
如果他们有很多共同点，也许他们是相似的。
So that's the idea.
这就是想法。
Look at shared words and use that to define
查看共享词并用它来定义
document distance.
文件距离。
This is obviously only one way to define distance.
显然，这只是定义距离的一种方法。
It'll be the way we do it in this class.
这将是我们在本课中做到的方式。
But there are lots of other possibilities.
但是还有许多其他可能性。
So I'm going to think of a document.
因此，我将考虑一个文档。
It's a sequence of words.
这是一个单词序列。
But I could also think of it as a vector.
但我也可以将其视为向量。
So if I have a document D and I have a word W, this D of W
因此，如果我有一个文档D并且我有一个单词W，则W的这个D
is going to be the number of times
将是次数
that word occurs in the document.
该单词出现在文档中。
So, number of recurrences W in the document D.
因此，文档D中的重复次数W。
So it's a number.
这是一个数字。
It's an integer.
这是一个整数。
Non-negative integer.
非负整数。
Could be 0.
可以为0。
Could be one.
可能是一个。
Could be a million.
可能是一百万。
I think of this as a giant vector.
我认为这是一个巨大的载体。
A vector is indexed by all words.
向量由所有单词索引。
And for each of them, there's some frequency.
对于每个人，都有一定的频率。
Of lot of them are zero.
其中许多为零。
And then some of them have some positive number occurrences.
然后其中一些出现了一些正数。
You could think of every document
您可以想到所有文件
is as being one of these plots in this common axis.
就像是在此公共轴上的这些图之一。
There's infinitely many words down here.
这里有无数的词。
So it's kind of a big axis.
所以这是一个很大的轴。
But it's one way to draw the picture.
但这是绘制图片的一种方法。
OK, so for example, take two very important documents.
好的，例如，拿两个非常重要的文件。
Everybody likes cats and dogs.
每个人都喜欢猫和狗。
So these are two word documents.
因此，这是两个Word文档。
And so we can draw them.
这样我们就可以绘制它们。
Because there's only three different words here,
因为这里只有三个不同的词，
we can draw them in three dimensional space.
我们可以在三维空间中绘制它们。
Beyond that, it's a little hard to draw.
除此之外，还很难绘制。
So we have, let's say, which one's the-- let's say
所以我们可以说，这是-
this one's the-- makes it easier to draw.
这是-使绘制更容易。
So there's going to be just zero here and one.
因此，这里将只有零个，一个。
For each of the axes, let's say this is dog and this is cat.
对于每个轴，假设这是狗，这是猫。
OK, so the cat has won the-- it has one cat and no dog.
好吧，那只猫赢了，它只有一只猫，没有一只狗。
So it's here.
就在这里。
It's a vector pointing out there.
这是一个指向那里的向量。
The dog you've got basically pointing there.
你的狗基本上都指向那里。
OK, so these are two vectors.
好的，所以这是两个向量。
So how do I measure how different two vectors are?
那么，如何测量两个向量有何不同？
Any suggestions from vector calculus?
向量演算有什么建议吗？
AUDIENCE: Inner product?
听众：内在的产品？
PROFESSOR: Inner product?
教授：内在产品？
Yeah, that's good suggestion.
是的，这是个好建议。
Any others.
任何其他。
OK, we'll go with inner product.
好的，我们将使用内部产品。
I like inner product, also known as dot product.
我喜欢内部产品，也称为点产品。
Just define that quickly.
只需快速定义即可。
So we could-- I'm going to call this D prime
所以我们可以-我将其称为D素数
because it's not what we're going to end up with.
因为这不是我们要最终得到的。
We could think of this as the dot product of D1 and D2,
我们可以认为这是D1和D2的点积，
also known as the sum over all words of D1 of W times D2 of W.
也称为W的D1的所有字的总和乘以W的D2。
So for example, you take the dot product of these two guys.
因此，例如，您采用这两个家伙的点积。
Those match.
那些比赛。
So you get one point there, cat and dog multiplied by zero.
这样一来，猫和狗乘以零就可以得到1分。
So you don't get much there.
所以你在那里没有很多。
So this is some measure of distance.
所以这是一些距离的量度。
But it's a measure of, actually, of commonality.
但这实际上是对通用性的衡量。
So it would be sort of inverse distance, sorry.
抱歉，这将是反距离。
If you have a high dot product, you
如果您有高点产品，那么您
have a lot of things in common.
有很多共同点。
Because a lot of these things didn't be--
因为很多事情不是-
wasn't zero times something.
不是零倍的东西。
It's actually a positive number times some positive number.
它实际上是一个正数乘以某个正数。
If you have a lot of shared words, than that looks good.
如果您有很多共同的词，那么看起来不错。
The trouble of this is if I have a long document--
问题是如果我的文档很长，
say, a million words-- and it's 99% in common
比方说一百万个字-共有99％
with another document that's a million words long,
还有另一本长达一百万字的文档，
it's still-- it looks super similar.
它仍然-看起来超级相似。
Actually, I need to do it the other way around.
实际上，我需要反过来做。
Let's say it's a million words long and half of the words
假设这是一百万个字，一半是字
are in common.
是共同的。
So not that many, but a fair number.
因此，数量不多，但数量不多。
Then I have a score of like 500,000.
那我的分数大约是500,000。
And then I have two documents which are, say, 100 words long.
然后我有两个文档，比如说100个字长。
And they're identical.
它们是相同的。
Their score is maybe only 100.
他们的分数可能只有100。
So even though they're identical,
因此，即使它们相同，
it's not quite scale invariant.
它不是规模不变的。
So it's not quite a perfect measure.
因此，这并不是一个完美的措施。
Any suggestions for how to fix this?
有关如何解决此问题的任何建议？
This, I think, is a little trickier.
我认为这有点棘手。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Divide by the length of the vectors?
听众：除以向量的长度？
PROFESSOR: Divide by the length of the vectors.
教授：除以向量的长度。
I think that's worth a pillow.
我认为这值得一个枕头。
Haven't done any pillows yet.
还没做枕头
Sorry about that.
对于那个很抱歉。
So, divide by the length of vector.
因此，除以向量的长度。
That's good.
那很好。
I'm going to call this D double prime.
我将其称为D双素数。
Still not quite the right answer.
仍然不是很正确的答案。
Or not-- no, it's pretty good.
还是不-不，这很好。
It's pretty good.
这是相当不错。
So here, the length of the vectors
所以在这里，向量的长度
is the number of words that occur
是出现的单词数
in them This is pretty cool.
在他们那里，这很酷。
But does anyone recognize this formula?
但是有人知道这个公式吗？
Angle, yeah.
角度，是的。
It's a lot like the angle between the two vectors.
这很像两个向量之间的角度。
It's just off by an arc cos.
刚刚被电弧cos关闭。
This is the cosine of the angle between the two vectors.
这是两个向量之间夹角的余弦。
And I'm a geometer.
我是几何学家。
I like geometry.
我喜欢几何。
So if you take arc cos of that thing,
所以，如果你把那个东西当作反角，
that's a well established distance metric.
这是一个公认的距离指标。
This goes back to '75, if you can believe it,
如果可以相信的话，可以追溯到75年
back when people-- early days of document, information
回到人们-文件，信息的早期
retrieval, way before the web, people
检索，网络之前的人们
were still working on this stuff.
仍在研究这些东西。
So it's a natural measure of the angle between the two vectors.
因此，这是两个向量之间夹角的自然度量。
If it's 0, they're basically identical.
如果为0，则基本上相同。
If it's 90 degrees, they're really, really different.
如果是90度，它们的确非常不同。
And so that gives you a nice way to compute document distance.
这样就为您提供了一种计算文档距离的好方法。
The question is, how do we actually compute that measure?
问题是，我们如何实际计算该度量？
Now that we've come up with something that's reasonable,
现在我们提出了合理的东西，
how do I actually find this value?
我实际上如何找到该值？
I need to compute these vectors-- the number
我需要计算这些向量-数字
of recurrences of each word in the document.
文档中每个单词的重复出现次数。
And I need you compute the dot product.
我需要您计算点积。
And then I need to divide.
然后我需要分开。
That's really easy.
真的很简单。
So, dot product-- and I also need
所以，点积-我也需要
to decompose a document to a list of words.
将文档分解为单词列表。
So there are three things I need to do.
因此，我需要做三件事。
Let me write them down.
让我写下来。
So a sort of algorithm.
所以是一种算法。
There's one, split a document into words.
有一个，将文档拆分为单词。
Second is compute word frequencies,
其次是计算单词频率
how many times each word appears.
每个单词出现多少次。
This is the document vectors .
这是文档向量。
And then the third step is to compute the dot product.
然后第三步是计算点积。
Let me tell you a little bit about how each of those
让我告诉您一些有关
is done.
已经完成了。
Some of these will be covered more in future lectures.
其中一些将在以后的讲座中介绍。
I want to give you an overview.
我想给你一个概述。
There's a lot of ways to do each of these steps.
有很多方法可以执行这些步骤。
If you look at the-- next to the lecture
如果您查看讲座旁边的-
notes for this lecture two, there's a bunch of code
关于本讲座二的注释，有一堆代码
and a bunch of data examples of documents--
和一堆文件的数据示例-
big corpuses of text.
大文本语料库。
And you can run, I think, there are
我想你可以跑步
eight different algorithms for it.
八个不同的算法。
And let me give you-- actually, why don't I
让我给你-实际上，我为什么不
cut to the chase a little bit and tell you
切入正题然后告诉你
about the run times of these different implementations
关于这些不同实现的运行时间
of this same algorithms.
同样的算法
There are lots of sort of versions of this algorithm.
此算法有多种版本。
We implement it a whole bunch.
我们实施了很多。
Every semester I teach this, I change them a little bit more,
我每学一个学期都会对此进行一些修改，
add a few more variants.
添加更多变体。
So version one, on a particular pair
所以在特定的一对上
of documents which is like a megabyte-- not very much text--
像兆字节的文档-文本不多-
it takes 228.1 seconds-- super slow.
需要228.1秒-超级慢。
Pathetic.
可悲的。
Then we do a little bit of algorithmic tweaking.
然后，我们进行一些算法调整。
We get down to 164 seconds.
我们下降到164秒。
Then we get to 123 seconds.
然后我们到达123秒。
Then we get down to 71 seconds.
然后我们下降到71秒。
Then we get down to 18.3 seconds.
然后我们下降到18.3秒。
And then we get to 11.5 seconds.
然后我们到达11.5秒。
Then we get to 1.8 seconds.
然后我们到达1.8秒。
Then we get to 0.2 seconds.
然后我们到达0.2秒。
So factor of 1,000.
因此，系数为1,000。
This is just in Python.
这只是在Python中。
2/10 of a second to process a megabytes.
2/10秒用于处理兆字节。
It's all right.
没关系。
It's getting reasonable.
越来越合理了。
This is not so reasonable.
这不是那么合理。
Some of these improvements are algorithmic.
其中一些改进是算法上的。
Some of them are just better coding.
其中一些只是更好的编码。
So there's improving the constant factors.
因此，不断改进的恒定因素。
But if you look at larger and larger texts,
但是，如果您看越来越大的文字，
this will become even more dramatic.
这将变得更加戏剧化。
Because a lot of these were improvements
因为这些都是很多改进
from quadratic time algorithms to linear and log n algorithms.
从二次时间算法到线性和log n算法。
And so for a megabyte, yeah, it's a reasonable improvement.
因此，对于一个兆字节，这是一个合理的改进。
But if you look at a gigabyte, it'll be a huge improvement.
但是，如果您查看千兆字节，那将是一个巨大的进步。
There will be no comparison.
不会有比较。
In fact, there will be no comparison.
实际上，将没有任何比较。
Because this one will never finish.
因为这个永远不会完成。
So the reason I ran such a small example
所以我跑了一个小例子的原因
so I could have patience to wait for this one.
因此我可以耐心等待。
But this one you could run on the bigger examples.
但是您可以使用更大的示例。
All right, so where do I want to go from here?
好吧，那我想从这里去哪里呢？
Five minutes.
5分钟。
I want to tell you about some of those improvements
我想告诉你一些改进
and some of the algorithms here.
以及此处的一些算法。
Let's start with this very simple one.
让我们从这个非常简单的例子开始。
How would you split a document into words in Python?
您将如何用Python将文档拆分成单词？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
Iterate through the document, [INAUDIBLE] the dictionary?
遍历文档，[听不清]字典？
PROFESSOR: Iterate through the-- that's
教授：遍历-
actually how we do number two.
实际上我们该怎么做第二。
OK, we can talk about that one.
好，我们可以谈一谈。
Iterate through the words in the document
遍历文档中的单词
and put it in a dictionary.
并放入字典中
Let's say, count of word plus equals 1.
假设字数加等于1。
This would work if count is something called a count
如果计数是所谓的计数，这将工作
dictionary if you're super Pythonista.
字典，如果您是超级Pythonista。
Otherwise, you have to check, is the word in the dictionary?
否则，您必须检查一下，词典中的单词是吗？
If not, set it to one.
如果不是，请将其设置为1。
If it is there, add one to it.
如果存在，则添加一个。
But I think you know what this means.
但是我想你知道这意味着什么。
This will count the number of words--
这将计算字数-
this will count the frequency of each word in the dictionary.
这将计算字典中每个单词的频率。
And becomes dictionaries run in constant time
并成为字典在恒定时间内运行
with high probability-- with high probability--
很有可能
this will take order-- well, cheating a little bit.
这需要命令-好吧，有点作弊。
Because words can be really long.
因为言语可能真的很长。
And so to reduce a word down to a machine word
这样就可以将单词简化为机器单词
could take order the length of the word time.
可以接受单词时间长度的排序。
To a little more precise, this is
更确切地说，这是
going to be the sum of the lengths
将是长度的总和
of the words in the document, which is also
文档中的单词
known as a length of the document, basically.
基本上称为文档的长度。
So this is good.
所以这很好。
This is linear time with high probability.
这是线性时间，概率很高。
OK, that's a good algorithm.
好的，这是一个很好的算法。
That is introduced in algorithm four.
在算法四中介绍。
So we got a significant boost.
因此，我们获得了巨大的推动。
There are other ways to do this.
还有其他方法可以做到这一点。
For example, you could sort the words
例如，您可以对单词进行排序
and then run through the sorted list
然后遍历排序列表
and count, how many do you get in a row for each one?
算一下，您每个人连续得到多少？
If it's sorted, you can count-- I mean,
如果排序的话，您可以数-我是说，
all the identical words are put right next to each other.
所有相同的词都紧挨着放置。
So it's easy to count them.
因此很容易计算它们。
And that'll run almost as fast.
而且运行速度几乎一样快。
That was one of these algorithms.
那是这些算法之一。
OK, so that's a couple different ways to do that.
好的，这是几种不同的方法。
Let's go back to this first step.
让我们回到第一步。
How would you split a document into words in the first place?
首先如何将文档拆分为单词？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: Search circulated spaces and then [INAUDIBLE].
听众：搜索循环的空格，然后搜索[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Run through though the string.
教授：贯穿字符串。
And every time you see anything that's not alphanumeric,
每次您看到非字母数字的内容时，
start a new word.
开始一个新词。
OK, that would run in linear time.
好的，那将在线性时间内运行。
That's a good answer.
那是一个很好的答案。
So it's not hard.
因此，这并不困难。
If you're a fancy Pythonista, you might do it like this.
如果您是个喜欢Pythonista的人，可以这样做。
Remember my Reg Exes.
记住我的Reg Exes。
This will find all the words in a document.
这将找到文档中的所有单词。
Trouble is, in general, re takes exponential time.
通常，麻烦是花费指数时间。
So if you think about algorithms, be very careful.
因此，如果您考虑算法，请务必小心。
Unless you know how re is implemented,
除非您知道如何实施re，
this probably will run in linear time.
这可能会线性运行。
But it's not obvious at all.
但这一点都不明显。
Do anything fancy with regular expressions.
用正则表达式做任何花哨的事情。
If you don't know what this means, don't worry about it.
如果您不知道这意味着什么，请不必担心。
Don't use it.
不要使用它。
If you know about it, be very careful in this class
如果您知道这一点，请在本节课中非常小心
when you use re.
当您使用re。
Because it's not always linear time.
因为它并不总是线性时间。
But there is an easy algorithm for this,
但这有一个简单的算法，
which is just scan through and look for alpha numerics.
只是扫描并寻找字母数字。
String them together.
将它们串在一起。
It's good.
很好。
There's a few other algorithms here in the notes.
注释中还有其他一些算法。
You should check them out.
你应该检查出来。
And for fun, look at this code and see how small differences
为了好玩，请看一下这段代码，看看有多么小的差异
make dramatic difference in performance.
在性能上产生巨大变化。
Next class will be about sorting.
下一堂课是关于排序的。